Guide to the Jack O'Brien Papers AIA.067
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: The Troubles in Northern Ireland, 1964-2017 (inclusive), 1971-1989 (bulk); 11.58 Linear Feet in 22 legal manuscripts box, 3 folders in an additional legal manuscripts box, 13 folders in an oversized box, 5 folders in an additional oversized box, rolled storage, and 3 folders in a shared 
  - Sub-series I.A: 1981 Hunger Strike, 1980-2020; 0.85 Linear Feet in one legal sized manuscript box, 2 folder in an oversized box, rolled storage, and 1 folder in an additional oversized box.
    - Calendar, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Congressman Mario Biaggi Newsletters, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Congressional Record, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - U.S. Government, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Don't Let Them Die in Silence!", undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Films about Hunger Strikes, 2016 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Fundraiser Flyers, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - The Irish American Voice, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Irish National Caucus, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Irish Northern Aid Committee (NORAID), 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Joint Resolution on the Hunger Strike, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - National H-Block/Armagh Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1980-1984 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "On this Day: Bobby Sands, Long Kesh Hunger Strikers, Passes Away", 2020 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Pamphlets, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Political Education Committee, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Posters, undated (Box 11, Folder 23, Box 57, Folder 11-12, Box 58, Folder 2, Box 61)
    - "We Support the Five Demands" Banner, undated (Box 63)
  - Sub-series I.B: Irish American Organizations, 1968-1997; 2.15 Linear Feet in 4 legal sized manuscript boxes, 12 folders in an additional legal sized manuscript box, 2 audiocassette tapes in media box, 1 DVD-R disc in a media box, and 1 folder in an oversized box
    This series focuses upon the many Irish American organizations active during the Troubles such as the Irish Northern Aid Committee, the Irish National Caucus, the Irish American Unity Committee, and the Irish American Defense Fund. These organizations worked to raise money and provide assistance to the Republican movement in Northern Ireland, as well as support members of the Northern Irish community impacted by the conflict.
    Materials in this series include newsletters, fundraising flyers, correspondence, audio cassettes, press releases, educational brochures, and photographs.
    - Active Irish Groups in the Washington, DC Area, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - American Committee for Ulster Justice, 1972-1977 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - American Irish Congress, 1985-1990 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - American Irish National Immigration Committee, 1968, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - American Irish Unity Committee, 1981-1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - American Irish Unity Committee - "Plastic Bullets/Denis Dillon", 1983 (Box Shared Tamiment 084, Audiocassette 067.0006)
    - American Irish Unity Committee - "Richard Harvey", 1983 (Box Shared Tamiment 084, Audiocassette 067.0007)
    - American Protestants for Truth About Ireland, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - The Amergael (Irish American Club), 1971-1978 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Ancient Order of the Hibernians, 1982-1986 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Association for Legal Justice, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Brian Fleming Defense Committee, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - The Celtic Network, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Committee for Support Colm Murphy, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Doors of Hope (Doirse Dochais), 1987-1989 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Freedom for all Ireland Committee, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Irish in Britain Representation Group, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Irish American Conference, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Irish American Defense Fund, 1983-1986 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Irish American Fenian Society, Inc., undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Irish American Information Service, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Irish American Legal Fund, 1974-1984 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Irish American Societies in the Washington DC-Maryland and Virginia Area, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Irish American Unity Conference, 1983-1996; cuid42449 (Box 13, Folder 1-4, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_12)
    - Irish National Caucus, 1976-1991 (Box 13, Folder 5, Box 14, Folder 1-4)
    - Irish National Congress, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Irish Northern Aid Committee (NORAID), 1971-1997 (Box 14, Folder 6, Box 15, Folder 1-2, Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Irish Republican Information Service, 1974-1979 (Box 15, Folder 3-5)
    - Justice for Ireland Committee, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - National Association for Irish Freedom, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Na Fianna Eireann (Irish Republican Youth Movement), 1985 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - National Council for Civil Liberties, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - National Council for Irish Americans, 1976-1982 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - National Visa Committee, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Northern Ireland Human Rights Review, 1991-1997 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Operation/USA, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Peace and Justice Directory, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Political Education Committee, 1977-1997 (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
    - United Ireland Coalition, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Sub-series I.C: Extradition Treaty, 1980-2012; 0.96 Linear Feet in 1 legal sized manuscript box, 7 folders in a second legal sized manuscript box, and 17 folders in a third legal sized manuscript box
    This series focuses upon the controversial U.S.-U.K. Extradition Treaties as they relate to Northern Ireland and the attempted extradition of IRA members from the U.S. back to the U.K. The series reflects public disapproval of the extradition treaties, attempts to stop the ratification of the treaties, and debates surrounding the treaties.
    This series contains newspaper clippings, correspondence with members of the U.S. government, press releases, newsletters, copies of the extradition treaties and related legislation, business cards, web printouts, memoranda circulated by various organizations like the Ancient Order of Hibernians and the Irish Northern Aid Committee, as well as official documents issued by the Senate.
    - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 2003-2006 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Americans Fight British in Senate: Claim Treaty Trashes U.S. Rights", 2006 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - AOH Ohio Action Plan/Battle Ribbons Project, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - AOH Statement Regarding Extradition Treaty, 1986, 2003-2006 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - The Annotated U.S.-U.K. Supplementary Extradition Treaty: A Short Guide to Understanding, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Baroness Scotland QC - US/UK Extradition Treaty, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Business Cards - Members of U.S. Government, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Chris Dodd Statement, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Congressman Mario Biaggi Newsletters, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Congressional Record, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Research Service Report for Congress, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1982, 1986, 2004, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and Letter Templates with U.S. Government, 1981-1986, 2004-2008 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Dick Lugar Reports, 1986, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Emails, 2004-2006, 2012 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - Extradition (Wikipedia), 2006 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Extradition Treaty (copies), 2003 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Fact Sheets, 1986, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Irish American Unity Conference, 1985-1986, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Irish Northern Aid Committee (NORAID), undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1980-1991, 2003-2006 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Political Education Committee, 1985-1986, 2003-2006 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases, 1985, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Question for Administration Witnesses", undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Resolution of Ratification for US-UK Supplementary Extradition Treaty, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Senate Judiciary Subcommittee on Security and Terrorism (SST), undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Statement of Mary Ellen Warlow, Director Office of International Affairs Criminal Division DOJ Re: Law Enforcements of Treaties, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Statement of Paul McNulty, Deputy Attorney General, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "Stop the Supplemental Extradition Treaty between the U.S. and Britain", undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Testimony of Francis A. Boyle, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Testimony of Samuel M. Witten, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Treaty Reference, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "U.S./U.K. Extradition Treaties", 2006 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Senate Bills, 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - U.S. Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 15-16)
    - U.S. Senate - Treaties, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Sub-series I.D: Press Clippings, 1969-1996; 2.16 Linear Feet in 4 legal sized manuscript boxes, 4 folders in a second legal sized manuscript box, 3 folders in a third legal sized manuscript box, 1 folder in an oversized box, and 3 folders in a shared oversized box
    This series focuses on the press coverage of the Troubles and contains news clippings from various newspapers.
    - Irish Newsletters in the Washington, DC Area, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - List of Irish and Irish American Newspapers, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1971-1995 (Box 18, Folder 20-21, Box 19, Folder 1-6, Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings - America, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings - An Phoblacht, 1982-1987 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Andersontown News, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Baltimore Chronicle, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Baltimore Sun, 1979-1986 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Boston Globe, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Boston Herald, 1976, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Buffalo Courier Express, 1969, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Buffalo Evening News, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Burntollet, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Catholic Standard, 1978-1984 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Christian Science Monitor, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Cork Examiner, 1986 (Box Shared Tamiment 081, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Counterspy, 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Current, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Daily Collegian, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Daily Mirror, 1980, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Daily News, 1971-1984 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Daily Press, 1974-1976 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Dallas Times Herald, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Derry Journal, 1984 (Box Shared Tamiment 081, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Derry Supplement, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Detriot Press Press, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper Clippings - District Star, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Evening Star, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Evening Sun, 1984, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Fortune, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Georgetown Voice, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Harper's, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Hibernia, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Hoya, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Irish Echo, 1976-1993 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Irish Edition, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Irish News, 1973, 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Irish People, 1971-1987 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Irish Post, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Irish Press, 1981-1984 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Irish Times, 1976-1983 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Life Magazine, undated (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Na Madrai, undated (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Nation, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The National Hibernian Digest, 1980-1988 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Newsday, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Newsweek, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The News American, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The New Scientist, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The New York Post, 1981-1983 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The New York Times, 1974-1989 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Next Step, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Observer, 1971-1977 (Box 21, Folder 9, Box Shared Tamiment 081, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Patriot, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Penthouse, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Philadelphia Daily News, 1981-1986 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Philadelphia Inquirer, 1983-1986 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Plain Dealer, 1982-1985 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Prince George's Star, 1981-1986 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Retriever, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Rolling Stones Magazine, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper Clippings - San Antonio News, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Shillelagh, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Standard, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Sun, 1974-1995 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Sunday Journal, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Sunday Press, 1981, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Sunday Times, 1985-1990 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Times, 1977-1986 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Times-Herald, 1974-1976 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Time Magazine, 1979, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Newspaper Clippings - US News and World Report, 1981-1987 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Newspaper Clippings - USA Today, 1982-1987 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Wall Street Journal, 1981-1985 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Washington Post, 1971-1996 (Box 21, Folder 31, Box 22, Folder 1-4)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Washington Star, 1973-1983 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings - The Washington Times, 1981-1996 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Reader's Digest - "Terror in Northern Ireland: The American Connection", 1983 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Series II: Northern Ireland Post-Troubles, 1998-2020; 4.37 Linear Feet in 7 legal sized manuscript boxes, 14 folders in a second legal sized manuscript box, 5 folders in a third legal sized manuscript box, 2 DVD-R discs in a media box, 1 folder in an oversized box, 1 folder in an additional oversized box, and 1 folder in a shared oversized box; 6.34 Gigabytes on 2 DVD-R discs
  This series focuses on Northern Ireland after the signing of the Good Friday Agreement in 1998. This agreement ended most of the violence in Northern Ireland and is considered the end point of the Troubles. This series focuses upon efforts towards a united Ireland, Brexit, Sinn Fein, as well as the legacy of the Troubles such as the arrest of Gerry Adams for the murder of Jean McConville and new evidence regarding the murder of Patrick Finucane. This series also contains papers related to the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE), also known as the U.S. Helsinki Commission.
  This series contains newsletters, correspondence, official reports, news clippings, press releases, posters, booklets, calendars, Congressional Records, book excerpts, emails, flyers, bumper stickers, brochures, and Good Friday Agreement commemoration materials.
  - Ag Aontu Eireann (Uniting Ireland), 2011-2012 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - The Agreement, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Ambush, Assassination, and Impunity: Killing of Kevin Barry O'Donnell, Patrick Vincent, Peter Clancy, and Sean O'Farrell, 2012 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - American Irish Newsletter, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "American's Purpose: Leadership for a New Secruity Consesus" (Sen. Joseph R. Biden), 2008 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Ancient Order of the Hibernians Memos, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Irish Defamation Federation, 2011 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Ballymurphy Massacre, 2011-2019 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Belfast Homecoming, 2015 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Belfast Media Group, 2015, 2017 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Bloody Sunday, 2010-2019 (Box 23, Folder 14, Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Book Excerpt - Remembering the Troubles (Jim Smyth), 2017 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Border Roads 1990-1994 (Tony O'Shea), 2017 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Brexit: UK-Irish Relations (House of Lords, European Union Committee), 2016 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Brexit, 2016-2019 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Brian Pearson Support Committee, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "British Army 'Covered Up' UDR Units links to UVF", 2011 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - British Information Services booklets, 1977, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Buttons, undated (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Calendars, 2014, 2019 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - A Campaign for a United Ireland, 2011-2017 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Can the Past Be Policed?: Lessons from the Historical Enquiries Team Northern Ireland, 2009 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - The Case for a United Ireland, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - "Catholic Bishops in Northern Ireland Criticise UK Government's Approach to Legacy of the Past", 2020 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - "The Chicago Four (1992)", 2017 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Mole Among Us, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Children's Friendship Project for Northern Ireland Inc., 2000 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Colin Duffy, 2009 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Coiste na n-Iarchimi, undated (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Coiste US Tour (Irish Northern Aid), 2005 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Commemorations and Fundraiser Flyers, 2012, 2019 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Conference Paper about Northern Ireland's Troubles, 2012 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Record, 2017 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2006, 2014-2018 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Gerry Adams, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Governments, 1999-2009 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Deportation of Irish Nationals in the United States, 2019 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Emails, 2014-2018 (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
  - Fact Sheets, 2013 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Father Des Wilson, 2009, 2016, 2019 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Father Sean McManus, 2009, 2012, 2017 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Fighting Terrorism in a Democratic Society, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Films about the IRA, 2016 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Flyers and Advertisements, 2011, 2013, 2018 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Free the Dunleavy Three, undated (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Friends of Sinn Fein, 2001, 2012-2020 (Box 25, Folder 15-16, Box 26, Folder 1, Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Gerard Lawler Community Inquiry, 2012 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Gerry Adams and 1972 Murder Charge of Jean McConville, 2014-2015 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Gerry Adams Blog Post on Irish Unity, 2020 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Gerry McGeough, 2009, 2012, 2016 (Box 26, Folder 5, Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Good Friday Agreement, 1993, 2013 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - The Good Friday Agreement at 20: Achievements and Unfinished Business, 2018 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - The Hidden History of the UDR: The Secret Files Revealed, 2014 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - The Holy Cross Ardoyne Trust, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Hooded Men Case, 2014 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - The Independent Monitoring Commission, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - "Invest in Northern Ireland" (Northern Ireland Bureau), undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - "Ireland: UK Fake News and Alternate Facts", undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Irish American Unity Conference, 1999-2019 (Box 26, Folder 14-15, Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Irish American Unity Conference, 2014; cuid42450 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_6)
  - Irish National Caucus, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Irish Northern Aid Committee (NORAID), 1998-2007, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 4, Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Irish POWs, 2015, 2017 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Irish Republican Army (IRA), 2001 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - "Irish Republican Army FBI Files", 2007 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - John Finucane, 2019-2020 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Justice Magazine (Relatives for Justice), 2001 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - List of Law and Civil LIberties Organizations, 2004 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Loughinisland Massacre, 2014 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - "Loyalist Paramilitary Displays in Rasharkin Must End", 2006 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Malachy McAllister Case, 1999-2019 (Box 27, Folder 13, Box 65, Folder 19)
  - Marian Price, 2011-2012 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Martin McGuiness, 2012, 2017, 2019 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Miami Showband Massacre, 2014, 2020 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Michael Cummings, 2012 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - New Belfast, 2014-2016 (Box 28, Folder 3, Box 65, Folder 21)
  - News Articles, 2009, 2015-2016 (Box 65, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1986, 1999-2019 (Box 28, Folder 4-8, Box 29, Folder 1-5, Box 65, Folder 22)
  - "Now is the Time to Stand Against the Anti-Good Friday Agreement Unionists", 2012 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Orange Order, 2007, 2017 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Overdue Bill of Rights: Northern Ireland, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Patrick Finucane and Rosemary Nelson, 1999, 2009, 2011-2013, 2016 (Box 30, Folder 3, Box 65, Folder 23)
  - Patriot Act, 2002-2005 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Pol Brennan (Deportation Case), 2009 (Box 65, Folder 24)
  - Political Education Committee, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 2009-2018 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Roll of Honor Commemorative Ceremony Flyer, undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - "SF Must Be Ready for Power" (Gerry Adams), 2005 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Say Nothing: A True Story of Murder and Memory in Northern Ireland, 2019 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Security and Freedom Enhanced (SAFE) Act, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Sinn Fein, 2000-2020 (Box 30, Folder 11, Box Shared Tamiment 081, Folder 10, Box 57, Box 65, Folder 27)
  - St. Patrick's Day 2014 and the Presence of the PSNI (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Stickers, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Strengthening America by Defending Our Liberties: An Agenda for Reform, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Summary Report: Sean Graham Bookmakers Atrocity, 2012 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Towards A United Ireland: A Sinn Fein Discussion Document, 2016 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Transnational Insurgency: Irish America, the IRA, and Northern Ireland's Troubles (Danielle A. Zach), 2016 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - United Ireland - Sinn Fein, 2009 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - United Ireland: Human Rights and International Law (Francis A. Boyle), 2011 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - United Ireland Resolution, 2011 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - United States Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (The Helsinki Commission), 2004-2018 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Unquiet Graves Documentary, 2016 (Box 31, Folder 5, Box 58, Folder 7)